Now, let's work through a form-filling exercise
from the IELTS Listening Section 1 together.
For this question type, the first step is
to read the requirement to identify the word
limit.
In this example, we are only allowed to
write a maximum of three words and a
number, and the shortest answer will be one
word or one number.
Step 2, we need to read the title
to understand the topic of the recording.
In this recording, we are going to
listen to a conversation about a graduate fair.
It is typically a conversation between a student
who is looking for a job and a
recruiter.
In this example, the main keywords are the
big headings.
In step 3, we are going to predict
what type of information is missing from each
blank.
For blank number 1, we need to hear
the spelling of a surname.
Blank number 2 is about nationality.
For blank number 3, we have to hear
the spelling of an email address.
For blank number 4, we need an adjective
to describe the BA degree.
The blank number 5 needs filling in a
date and a month.
Please pay attention to numbers ending with teen
or T.
Now it's your turn to predict what type
of information we should listen for in blanks
6 to 10.
Well done with the first three steps.
Next, you will listen to the recording and
write the answers in the blanks.
And don't forget to check the answers after you listen.
Good luck and see you soon!